Marzia Catherine Azam

+44 7 384 374 554 • azam.analytics@gmail.com
 LinkedIn: sanardiazam • Github: Sanardi • Portfolio: https://datanalysis.ai

Full Stack Software Engineer / Data Scientist

Google Cloud certified Python Engineer with a background in Applied Mathematics and Statistics and 6 years experience building Al Applications. Strong System/Mathematical thinking, especially iterative methods, Statistical Modeling, Vector Algebra.

An Engineer at heart I am driven by continuously expanding my knowledge of Cloud, Big Data and AI, especially structured and semi-structured data, and hold advanced certificates in Natural Language Processing (NLP). More recently I started writing code in Golang and would like to apply what I learned to problems requiring speed/concurrency where applicable.

Core Competencies

- Back-end Engineering: Design and Implementation of Data/ AI Applications: I build web-services
 (REST) using MySQL, PostgreSQL, Mongo, DB, Python Flask WSGI Nginx, Ubuntu, Docker, for
 re-indexing, accumulating web-scraped data, time-series charts as REST service, AI predictions,
 classification, geo-coding. Built on GCP, IBM, GCP, Microsoft Azure using ORM for relational Dbs.
- Data Science + Artificial Intelligence: Python (incl. Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn) Regression + Classification (ScikitLearn), NLP

Professional Experience

Senior Data Scientist / Data Engineer (2020 – present)

DAT Iberica Automotive, Europe
Design, Implementation, and Management of a business intelligence tool for data mining and processing.

Full stack Software / Data Engineering, including:

- Database setup and administration, MS Azure;
- Ubuntu / Python back-end that scrapes and classifies data, geo-coding using Google Location API, visualizations, reports and forecasts using scientific programming libraries and SciKitlearn;
- Front-end with interactive graphical dashboard using Flask and PlotlyDash

Python Developer/ Statistical Programmer (2014 – 2019)

Freelance, Europe

Contract work for previous employer ValueWorks LLC, alongside project-based data analysis, Time-series forecasting for Business Intelligence, market research, financial sector, medical research using Tableau,

Google Data Studio, BigQuery, GCP App Engine GCP Kubernetes Engine, GCP Cloud ML, some integrations with AWS S3 and ElasticSearch and a passion for research across many varied fields.

Built multiple back-ends from scratch that serve ML models on Linux. Also Azure Compute Instance, GCP Compute Engine with Ubuntu18.04, Docker, Nginx, Flask (MySQL, PostgreSQL or MongoDB, depending on Use-case -some all by myself, some as part of a team).

Research Associate / Hedgefund Accountant (2007 - 2009) ValueWorks LLC, New York, USA

Review of composite construction and performance in compliance with GIPS (CFA Institute), administration and reconciliation of brokerage accounts, equity and fixed income Trading, Performance Measurement using Bloomberg terminal, Preparation of Financial Statements for Hedge Fund, Investment Research.

Junior Manager (2001 – 2004)

Siemens AG, Munich, Germany

Assisted Team of UI Developers of Siemens Mobile Phones: full charge of design, evaluation and interpretation of a market research study using SPSS.

Education & Credentials

2021

Google Cloud Data Engineer Professional Building Streaming Analytics Pipelines with GCP Building Batch Data Pipelines with GCP	Google Google Google
Modernizing Data Lakes and Data Warehouses with GCP 2020	Google
Building Transformer-Based Natural Language Processing Applications	NVIDIA
Natural Language Processing with Classification and Vector Spaces Fitting Statistical Models to data with Python Cloud Engineer Bootcamp	Deeplearning.ai University of Michigan The Linux Foundation
IT Automation with Python	Google
Neural Networks and Deep Learning – Andrew NG 2019	Deeplearning.ai
2017	
Al Engineering Databases and SQL for Data Science	IBM IBM
Databases and SQL for Data Science 2017 Certificate, Design and interpretation of clinical trials	IBM
Databases and SQL for Data Science 2017 Certificate, Design and interpretation of clinical trials 2016 MSc. Applied Science, Systems Engineering 2014	IBM John Hopkins University Sheffield University
Databases and SQL for Data Science 2017 Certificate, Design and interpretation of clinical trials 2016 MSc. Applied Science, Systems Engineering	IBM John Hopkins University